JULIAN SOSA

UI / FRONTEND DEVELOPER

EMAIL: hiJulianSosa@gmail.com WEBSITE: https://hijuliancode.github.io/ PHONE: +57 3234957933

TWITTER: hijuliansosa LINKEDIN: /in/hijuliansosa GITHUB: hijuliancode

SUMMARY

Julian is a Front end developer with experience building scalable web applications with state of the art technology. He has extensive knowledge of front-end JavaScript and browser APIs as well as significant experience with popular frameworks and libraries like React, Angular, Firebase.

SKILLS

JavaScript, ReactJS, Angular, AngularJS, jQuery, HTML, CSS, BEM, Bootstrap, Progressive Enhancement, Photoshop, Sass-Less-Stylus, SketchApp3, Git, UI Design, Gulp, Responsive Web Design, Terminal, Flexbox, Grid, AdobeXD, Figma Design, Self Learning, MongoDB, NodeJS API Rest

EMPLOYMENT

Webcreek LLC, UI Developer / Front End Stylist, Medellin - Colombia

Mar. 2019 - Feb. 2020

- Develop applications using modern front-end frameworks and back-end frameworks such as ES6, Angular, React, Ionic, Sass. Bootstrap, webpack.
- Define Frontend technology stack strategy and vision for websites, mobile applications and other interactive digital experiences.
- · Design and Develop complex software applications, Wireframing, Prototyping and Coding.

Lenspire, FrontEnd Web Engineer, USA - Remote Job

Dec. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- Built and optimized web components with AngularJS
- Gulp, Sass, Git, Javascript, AngularJS, Sketch, Photoshop.
- Coded landing pages
- Implemented HTML and CSS of Web Applications
- · Design and Develop complex software applications, Wireframing, Prototyping and Coding.

Barista Ventures, Front end web developer, Medellín - Remote Job - Colombia May 2015 - Dec. 2018

- · Built and optimized web components with AngularJS and ReactJS
- Gulp, Sass, SemanticUI, Git, Javascript, AngularJS, ReactJS, Redux, Sketch, Photoshop.
- · Designed and coded landing pages
- Improved HTML and CSS code by deleting unnecessary code
- Improved web-fonts implementation
- · Participated on the design process of mobile applications
- Used Sketch and Photoshop to design app views
- Wrote application specs

XumaK, LLC, Front end web developer, Medellín - Colombia

Jan. 2015 - Apr. 2015

- · Optimized code on web apps
- Refactored HTML and CSS code
- · Reviewed HTML and CSS to delete unnecessary code
- · Javascript development

Not The Same, Front end web developer, Bogotá - Colombia

Sept. 2013 - Jan. 2015

- · Landing Pages and Web pages development from Scratch, with and without frameworks
- Email & Newsletter Development, Support of different email platforms

EDUCATION

Make it Real Camp

Front end developer 2017

Bootcamp specialized in JavaScript, Angular, ReactJS, Redux, Firebase, JQuery, Ajax and Git, HTML and CSS3.

SENA

Programación de Software 2013

Government institution. I Acquired JavaScript, Algorithms, PHP, HTML5 and CSS skills.

VOLUNTEERING

Soldier on Colombian National Army

Nov. 2009 - Nov. 2011

- Passion for my work
- Work under pressure.
- Handle positions of trust.
- Organization/Management teams.
- Training should be so strong that the war/practice is a rest.